<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roberto Yus | DAMS Research Group</title>
    <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/author/roberto-yus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://damslabumbc.github.io/author/roberto-yus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Roberto Yus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Roberto Yus </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://damslabumbc.github.io/author/roberto-yus/avatar_hud9f680d9fd0901e8096a1696fa9f0d54_346067_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Roberto Yus</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/author/roberto-yus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-zyBench: Using Co-Simulation and Digital Twins to Benchmark Thermal Comfort Provision in Smart Buildings</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenAIPABench</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/genaipabench/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/genaipabench/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy policies of websites are often lengthy and intricate. Privacy assistants assist in simplifying policies and making them more accessible and user-friendly. The emergence of generative AI (genAI) offers new opportunities to build privacy assistants that can answer users&#39; questions about privacy policies. However, genAI&amp;rsquo;s reliability is a concern due to its potential for producing inaccurate information. This study introduces GenAIPABench, a benchmark for evaluating Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants (GenAIPAs). GenAIPABench includes: 1) A set of questions about privacy policies and data protection regulations, with annotated answers for various organizations and regulations; 2) Metrics to assess the accuracy, relevance, and consistency of responses; and 3) A tool for generating prompts to introduce privacy documents and varied privacy questions to test system robustness. We evaluated three leading genAI systems—ChatGPT-4, Bard, and Bing AI—using GenAIPABench to gauge their effectiveness as GenAIPAs. Our results demonstrate significant promise in genAI capabilities in the privacy domain while also highlighting challenges in managing complex queries, ensuring consistency, and verifying source accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEMSA: a DT-enabled Middleware for Self-adaptive Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/midd4dt-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/midd4dt-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GENAIPABENCH: A Benchmark for Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/genaipa-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/genaipa-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrivacyLens</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/privacylens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/privacylens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PrivacyLens is a novel framework devised to automatically collect, analyze, and publish privacy policies of smart IoT devices, responding to the growing concerns over user privacy as smart devices become increasingly integrated into daily lives. Despite the existence of privacy policies, a significant challenge arises as they are often overlooked or misunderstood by users, hence the need for an automated analysis to provide clearer insights to users and other stakeholders. Unlike previous works, this project pivots towards addressing the gap in privacy policies specific to smart devices which present unique challenges in collection and analysis due to their dispersed nature across various manufacturers and e-commerce platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PrivacyLens framework operates in three core stages; Collection, Analysis, and Publication. Initially, it crawls prominent e-commerce sites for smart IoT devices, extracting metadata and privacy policies, while also utilizing the Wayback Machine to garner historical privacy policies for longitudinal analysis. Following the collection, the framework employs Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Machine Learning (ML) techniques to dissect these policies, aiming to deduce features like overall quality, readability, and ambiguity among others. The final stage sees the publishing of this analyzed data on a dedicated website, updated monthly to provide users, policy authors, and regulators a robust, updated resource to understand and compare privacy practices across a multitude of smart devices. As of the submission, PrivacyLens has successfully amassed and analyzed over 1,200 privacy policies for 7,300 smart devices, presenting a significant stride towards fostering transparency and informed decision-making in the realm of smart device privacy. Through PrivacyLens, stakeholders varying from ordinary consumers to data protection regulators are equipped with a powerful tool to understand and navigate the privacy landscape of IoT devices, marking a crucial step towards creating a more responsible and transparent digital ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrivacyLens: A Framework to Collect and Analyze the Landscape of Past, Present, and Future Smart Device Privacy Policies</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/privacylens-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/privacylens-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Shot Federated Group Collaborative Filtering</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/icmla-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/icmla-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentaur: Sensor Observable Data Model for Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/cikm-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/cikm-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SemIoTic Ecosystem: A Semantic Bridge between IoT Devices and Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/acmtoit-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/acmtoit-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartSPEC: Customizable Smart Space Datasets via Event-Driven Simulations</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JENNER: Just-in-time Enrichment in Query Processing</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOCATER: Cleaning WiFi Connectivity Datasets for Semantic Localization</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb3-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb3-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Privacy-Enabled Platform for COVID-19 Applications</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from testbeds to ships: an experience study in deploying the TIPPERS Internet of Things platform to the US Navy</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/jdms-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/jdms-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sieve: A Middleware Approach to Scalable Access Control for Database Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartBench: A Benchmark For Data Management In Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb2-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb2-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstracting Interactions with IoT Devices Towards a Semantic Vision of Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemIoTic: Bridging the Semantic Gap in IoT Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-demo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-demo-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustworthy Privacy Policy Translation in Untrusted IoT Environments</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/iotbds-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/iotbds-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring fairness in participatory thermal comfort control in smart buildings</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
