<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DAMS Research Group</title>
    <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://damslabumbc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>DAMS Research Group</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Roberto Yus </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://damslabumbc.github.io/media/icon_hu302981aa99fa15a8a6e0a46294dd9bb8_23619_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>DAMS Research Group</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;UMBC DAMS Research Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; consists of faculty and students from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csee.umbc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Departments of Computer Science and Electrical Engineering&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.umbc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC)&lt;/a&gt;, located in Baltimore, MD, USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research focuses on four main areas of reseach: Data Management, Knowledge Representation &amp;amp; Reasoning, Privacy, and the IoT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joining-us&#34;&gt;Joining us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are always interested in working with new people. We hold weekly research meetings during the academic year that are open to visitors. You are welcome to join us to find out what we are working on. Please contact us if you are in government or industry and interested in collaborative research, are a prospective graduate student interest in applying our graduate programs, or are currently a UMBC undergraduate student who would like to get involved with research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;visiting&#34;&gt;Visiting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know if you would like to visit. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csee.umbc.edu/about/visiting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is more information explaining how to reach UMBC and the CSEE department.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the DAMS group</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/join/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group welcomes applicants from any race, ethnicity, religion, national origin, gender identity, gender expression, caregiver and family commitments, political affiliation, sexual orientation, and eligible age or disability status. Furthermore, we are committed to maintaining a supportive and collaborative group environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://damslabumbc.github.io/uploads/DAMS_groupPolicies.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our group policies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;graduate-students&#34;&gt;Graduate Students&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in pursuing a Ph.D. with either direct or general admit, or in thesis or project-based masters research, reach out to Prof. Yus by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryus@umbc.edu&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; with your: (1) CV, (2) a description of research experience and interests, and (3) specific information about why the DAMS group interests you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;applying-to-our-graduate-program&#34;&gt;Applying to our graduate program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in applying to the UMBC Computer Science graduate program, please check the information our the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csee.umbc.edu/CSEE/grad/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CSEE Grad programs&lt;/a&gt;. Graduate admissions are done by a central Departmental committee that processes all applications and decides on admissions for the entire department. Individual faculty members may not accept students on their own but reach out to Prof. Yus by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryus@umbc.edu&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in applying and potentially being part of the DAMS group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;undergraduate-students&#34;&gt;Undergraduate Students&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students majoring in Computer Science are encouraged to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous research experience is not required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students must be able to work an average of 10 hour per week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrated leadership and collaboration experience is a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong communication skills (written and oral) are a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of programming languages (e.g., Java, Python), Web development (e.g., HTML, Javascript, React), and Databases (e.g., MySQL, PostgreSQL) are a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-do-research&#34;&gt;Why do research?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through undergraduate research, you’ll: 1) learn about the latest questions currently under scientific investigation and approaches being used to tackle them, 2) help solve real and important scientific problems, and 3) gain valuable experience in critical thinking, problem solving, collaboration, and communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-will-you-do&#34;&gt;What will you do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAMS Group is focused on designing mechanisms to make IoT systems bridge the gap between user requirements and IoT device capabilities. Undergraduate researchers will generally work on projects related to the research areas of the group: 1) Data Management, 2) AI (Knowledge Representation &amp;amp; Reasoning), and 3) Privacy. These may involve activities such as interacting with IoT devices and systems, writing code to extract insights from sensor data, integrate ML algorithms within an IoT system, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-hours-for-the-position&#34;&gt;What are the hours for the position?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from attendance at weekly group meetings, students are free to work according to a flexible schedule. So far during COVID, all work has been remote, though we do have a lab office available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-apply&#34;&gt;How do I apply?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in applying for a lab position or for research credit, you must read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://damslabumbc.github.io/uploads/DAMS_Expectations_UGrad.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DAMS Group Undergraduate Research Agreement&lt;/a&gt; carefully to make sure you understand what’s involved. Then include in a single email: (1) your resume (PDF), (2) unofficial copy of your transcript (PDF); freshman can send high school transcript (PDF), and (3) one page or less explaining why you&amp;rsquo;d like to work in our lab (PDF). To write this well, I suggest you look at some of our papers from the last few years to orient yourself to our current projects. Make the subject of your email &amp;ldquo;Undergrad Application&amp;rdquo; and send this to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryus@umbc.edu&#34;&gt;Prof. Yus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Page content inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://atomslab.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ATOMS lab @ UMBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This website doesn’t collect or store any visitor data, period&lt;/strong&gt;. I made a conscious choice not to have analytics or comment system (e.g., disqus) on this website to minimize any indirect tracking that may happen. Please let me know if you notice anything on this website that doesn’t follow this principle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster accepted for presentation at UMBC&#39;s URCAD 2023</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-8-2023-umbc-urcad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-8-2023-umbc-urcad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our undergrad team looking at privacy issues on smart homes (Tartela, Luke, Ruhshana, and Josh) will present a poster during UMBC&amp;rsquo;s Undergraduate Research and Creative Achievement Day (URCAD) 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyzing Privacy and Utility Tradeoffs in Smart Homes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tartela Tabassum, Luke Zimmermann, Ruhshana Bobojonova, Joshua Cheeks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this research is to explore the trade-off that exists between privacy and utility when using smart devices at home. Smart speakers, doorbells, and TVs are becoming pervasive but raise important privacy concerns. For instance, by collecting audio and video, one could learn private information about us such as our age, emotions, socioeconomic status, and health conditions. To increase trust, there is a need to inform people about potentially sensitive inferences that can be made about them by smart devices and give them a choice to consent to it. We have built a prototype of a framework, using open-source code and AI/ML algorithms, that generates inferences about an individual based on audio (e.g., speech data collected by a smart speaker) and video (e.g., images collected by a smart security camera). The framework also allows the user to select which of these inferences should be &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo;. We have explored different mechanisms to hide those inferences while preserving utility such as: removing specific portions of audio/video that can lead to whether the person might be facing a respiratory disease or modifying the pitch/tone to hide their age and mood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Shot Federated Group Collaborative Filtering</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/icmla-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/icmla-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at ICMLA 2022</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/9-1-2022-icmla/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/9-1-2022-icmla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on one-shot federated learning has been accepted at ICMLA 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One-Shot Federated Group Collaborative Filtering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maksim E. Eren (UMBC/LANL), Manish Bhattarai (LANL), Nicholas Solovyev (LANL), Luke E. Richards (UMBC), Roberto Yus (UMBC), Charles Nicholas (UMBC), Boian S. Alexandrov (LANL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) with missing-value completion is a well-known effective Collaborative Filtering (CF) method used to provide personalized user recommendations. However, traditional CF relies on a privacy-invasive collection of user data to build a central recommender model. One-shot federated learning has recently emerged as a method to mitigate the privacy problem while addressing the traditional communication bottleneck of federated learning. In this paper, we present the first one-shot federated CF implementation, named One-FedCF, for groups of users or collaborating organizations. In our solution, the clients first apply local CF in-parallel to build distinct, client-specific recommenders. Then, the privacy-preserving local item patterns and biases from each client are shared with the processor to perform joint factorization in order to extract the global item patterns. Extracted patterns are then aggregated to each client to build the local models via knowledge distillation. In our experiments, we demonstrate the feasibility of our approach with two MovieLens datasets. One-FedCF can obtain results competitive with the state-of-the-art federated recommender systems at a substantial decrease in the number of communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at CIKM 2022</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/8-1-2022-sentaur-cikm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/8-1-2022-sentaur-cikm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on supporting sensor-based smart space analytical applications has been accepted at CIKM 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sentaur: Sensor Observable Data Model for Smart Spaces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peeyush Gupta, Sharad Mehrotra (University of California, Irvine); Shantanu Sharma (New Jersey Institute of Technology); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County); and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents Sentaur, a middleware designed, built, and deployed to support sensor-based smart space analytical applications. Sentaur supports a powerful data model that decouples semantic data (about the application domain) from sensor data (using which the semantic data is derived). By supporting mechanisms to map/translate data, concepts, and queries between the two levels, Sentaur relieves application developers from having to know or reason about either capabilities of sensors or write sensor specific code. This paper describes Sentaur data model, its translation strategy, and highlights its benefits through real-world case studies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentaur: Sensor Observable Data Model for Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/cikm-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/cikm-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at VLDB 2022</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/6-16-2022-jenner-vldb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/6-16-2022-jenner-vldb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on supporting query-time enrichment has been accepted at VLDB 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;JENNER:  Just-in-time Enrichment in Query Processing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dhrubajyoti Ghosh, Peeyush Gupta, and Sharad Mehrotra (University of California, Irvine); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County); and Yasser Altowim (Saudi Data and Artificial Intelligence Authority)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging domains, such as sensor-driven smart spaces and social media analytics, require incoming data to be enriched prior to its use. Enrichment often consists of machine learning (ML) functions that are too expensive/infeasible to execute at ingestion. We develop a strategy entitled Just-in-time ENrichmeNt in quERy Processing (JENNER) to support interactive analytics over data as soon as it arrives for such application context. JENNER exploits the inherent tradeoffs of cost and quality often displayed by the ML functions to  progressively improve query answers during query execution. We describe how JENNER works for a large class of SPJ and aggregation queries that form the bulk of  data analytics workload. Our experimental results on real datasets (IoT and Tweet) show that JENNER achieves progressive answers performing significantly better than the naive strategies of achieving progressive computation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UMBC faculty Karimi and Yus help team win 2nd place in Sandpit Challenge on Digital Trust</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-15-2022-incs-coe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-15-2022-incs-coe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A research team that includes UMBC CSEE faculty Naghmeh Karimi and Roberto Yus won the second place prize in the 2022 INCS-CoE Sandpit Challenge on Digital Trust. The International Cyber Security Center of Excellence (INCS-CoE) is an international collaboration of government, industry, and academic organizations that have partnered to explore pioneering efforts to address cybersecurity challenges created by a growing borderless digital society.  UMBC is a charter member of INCS-CoE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The INCS-COE Sandpit Challenge invited self-assembled teams to compete for seed research funding prizes to pursue their work further. The UMBC faculty teamed up with researchers from Royal Holloway (UK) and Keio University (Japan). They were awarded second prize for their proposal to deal with challenges associated with developing an International Digital Trust Framework. In particular, their project proposal focused on designing an ontology-based interoperability solution amongst the US, UK, and Japan for mutual recognition of trust, capturing private and public sector use cases with different assurance levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at ACM TOIT</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-27-2022-semiotic-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-27-2022-semiotic-journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on facilitating the administration of smart spaces has been accepted in ACM Transactions on Internet Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SemIoTic Ecosystem: A Semantic Bridge between IoT Devices and Smart Spaces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, USA); Sharad Mehrotra and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart space administration and application development is challenging in part due to the semantic gap that exists between the high-level requirements of users and the low-level capabilities of IoT devices. The stakeholders in a smart space are required to deal with communicating with specific IoT devices, capturing data, processing it, and abstracting it out to generate useful inferences. Additionally, this makes reusability of smart space applications difficult since they are developed for specific sensor deployments. In this paper, we present a holistic approach to IoT smart spaces, the SemIoTic ecosystem, to facilitate application development, space management, and service provision to its inhabitants. The ecosystem is based on a centralized repository, where developers can advertise their space-agnostic applications; and a SemIoTic system deployed in each smart space that interacts with those applications to provide them with the required information. SemIoTic applications are developed using a metamodel that defines high-level concepts abstracted from the smart space about the space itself and the people within it. Application requirements can be expressed then in terms of user-friendly high-level concepts which are automatically translated by SemIoTic into sensor/actuator commands adapted to the underlying device deployment in each space. We present a reference implementation of the ecosystem that has been deployed at the University of California, Irvine and is abstracting data from hundreds of sensors in the space and providing applications to campus members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best paper award at PerCom 2022!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-25-2022-percom-smartspec-best-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-25-2022-percom-smartspec-best-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the generation of realistic synthetic IoT datasets won the Mark Weiser Best Paper Award at IEEE PERCOM 2022!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SmartSPEC: Customizable Smart Space Datasets via Event-Driven Simulations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Chio (University of California, Irvine, USA); Daokun Jiang (Google); Peeyush Gupta (University of California, Irvine, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, USA); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Sharad Mehrotra and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents SmartSPEC, an approach to generate customizable smart space datasets using sensorized spaces in which people and events are embedded. Smart space datasets are critical to design, deploy and evaluate robust systems and applications to ensure cost-effective operation and safety/comfort/convenience of the space occupants. Often, real-world data is difficult to obtain due to the lack of fine-grained sensing; privacy/security concerns prevent the release and sharing of individual and spatial data. SmartSPEC is a smart space simulator and data generator that can create a digital representation (twin) of a smart space and its activities. SmartSPEC uses a semantic model and ML-based approaches to characterize and learn attributes in a sensorized space, and applies an event-driven simulation strategy to generate realistic simulated data about the space (events, trajectories, sensor datasets, etc). To evaluate the realism of the data generated by SmartSPEC, we develop a structured methodology and metrics to assess various aspects of smart space datasets, including trajectories of people and occupancy of spaces. Our experimental study looks at two real-world settings/datasets: an instrumented smart campus building and a city-wide GPS dataset. Our results show that the trajectories produced by SmartSPEC are 1.4x to 4.4x more realistic than the best synthetic data baseline when compared to real-world data, depending on the scenario and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartSpec</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/smartspec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/smartspec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SmartSPEC is a smart space simulator and data generator that creates customizable smart space datasets using semantic models of spaces, people, events and sensors. We employ ML-based approaches to characterize and learn attributes of the embedded people and events in a sensorized space and apply an event-driven simulation strategy to generate realistic simulated data about the space (events, trajectories, sensor datasets, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SmartSPEC architecture consists of two main components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario Learning, which uses input seed connectivity data and a priori knowledge of the underlying space and sensors to learn high-order concepts of events, people and trajectories, which we refer to as &amp;ldquo;metaevents&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;metapeople&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;metatrajectories&amp;rdquo;, respectively; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario Generation, which takes SmartSPEC data to generate a synthetic dataset from which a smart space dataset (e.g., trajectory dataset, sensor observation dataset, etc.) can be derived. We use the variations of the data models described below to define various scenarios, which drives the generation of new observable phenomena in the smart space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SemIoTic Ecosystem: A Semantic Bridge between IoT Devices and Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/acmtoit-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/acmtoit-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartSPEC: Customizable Smart Space Datasets via Event-Driven Simulations</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at PerCom 2022!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/2-14-2022-percom-smartspec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/2-14-2022-percom-smartspec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the generation of realistic synthetic IoT datasets has been accepted at PerCom 2022. The paper has also been nominated for best paper award! More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.percom.org/full-program/#session5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PerCom 2022 website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SmartSPEC: Customizable Smart Space Datasets via Event-Driven Simulations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Chio (University of California, Irvine, USA); Daokun Jiang (Google); Peeyush Gupta (University of California, Irvine, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, USA); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Sharad Mehrotra and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents SmartSPEC, an approach to generate customizable smart space datasets using sensorized spaces in which people and events are embedded. Smart space datasets are critical to design, deploy and evaluate robust systems and applications to ensure cost-effective operation and safety/comfort/convenience of the space occupants. Often, real-world data is difficult to obtain due to the lack of fine-grained sensing; privacy/security concerns prevent the release and sharing of individual and spatial data. SmartSPEC is a smart space simulator and data generator that can create a digital representation (twin) of a smart space and its activities. SmartSPEC uses a semantic model and ML-based approaches to characterize and learn attributes in a sensorized space, and applies an event-driven simulation strategy to generate realistic simulated data about the space (events, trajectories, sensor datasets, etc). To evaluate the realism of the data generated by SmartSPEC, we develop a structured methodology and metrics to assess various aspects of smart space datasets, including trajectories of people and occupancy of spaces. Our experimental study looks at two real-world settings/datasets: an instrumented smart campus building and a city-wide GPS dataset. Our results show that the trajectories produced by SmartSPEC are 1.4x to 4.4x more realistic than the best synthetic data baseline when compared to real-world data, depending on the scenario and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JENNER: Just-in-time Enrichment in Query Processing</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DAMS Research Group is officially launched!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/10-24-21-group-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/10-24-21-group-starts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DAta Management &amp;amp; Semantics (DAMS) research group starts at the University of Maryland, Baltimore County.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOCATER: Cleaning WiFi Connectivity Datasets for Semantic Localization</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb3-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb3-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Privacy-Enabled Platform for COVID-19 Applications</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/sensys-demo-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from testbeds to ships: an experience study in deploying the TIPPERS Internet of Things platform to the US Navy</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/jdms-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/jdms-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sieve: A Middleware Approach to Scalable Access Control for Database Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartBench: A Benchmark For Data Management In Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb2-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/vldb2-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstracting Interactions with IoT Devices Towards a Semantic Vision of Smart Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemIoTic: Bridging the Semantic Gap in IoT Spaces</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-demo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-demo-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemIoTic</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/semiotic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/project/semiotic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SemIoTic is a middleware framework for IoT smart spaces that provides application developers and end-users with a semantic domain-relevant view of a smart space 
while hiding the complexity of having to deal with/understand lower-level information generated by sensors and actuators. SemIoTic uses a metamodel based on the popular 
SOSA/SSN ontology with some extensions to represent relationships between the low-level IoT devices&#39; world (i.e., devices, observations) and semantic concepts 
(i.e., observable attributes of users and spaces). It supports a language where users can express their action requirements (i.e., requests for sensor data, commands 
for actuators, and privacy preferences) in terms of user-friendly high-level concepts. We present an ontology-based algorithmic approach to translate user-defined actions 
into sensor/actuators commands. Finally, our end-to-end approach includes a cross-layer solution to provide interoperability with diverse IoT devices and their data exchange protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several instances of SemIoTic have been deployed and used in IoT spaces. At the Donald Bren Hall building of UC Irvine, building occupants 
have access to Concierge and Building Analytics smart applications and building administrators have access to a Contact Tracing Application to help combat the spread of COVID-19.
Also, SemIoTic has been deployed inside a navy ship from the Naval Information Warfare Center (NIWC) 
in the context of the Trident Warrior exercise 2019/2020. SemIoTic enabled testing of applications such as occupancy analysis in multiple 
regions of the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;useful-links-and-references&#34;&gt;Useful links and references&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SemIoTic is developed as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tippers.ics.uci.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TIPPERS&lt;/a&gt; (Testbed for IoT-based Privacy-Preserving PERvasive Spaces) DARPA research project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustworthy Privacy Policy Translation in Untrusted IoT Environments</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/iotbds-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/iotbds-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring fairness in participatory thermal comfort control in smart buildings</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/buildsys-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
