<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | DAMS Research Group</title>
    <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Roberto Yus </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://damslabumbc.github.io/media/icon_hu302981aa99fa15a8a6e0a46294dd9bb8_23619_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo paper accepted at SmartComp 2025!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-13-2025-smartcompdemo-accepted/5-13-2025-smartcompdemo-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-13-2025-smartcompdemo-accepted/5-13-2025-smartcompdemo-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team’s demo paper has been officially accepted to be demoed at the IEEE International Conference on Smart Computing (SmartComp) 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Web-CozyBench: A Web-Based Platform to Benchmark Thermal Comfort Provision using Digital Twins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun Ma, Aziz Boubaker, Sabrine Azaiez (Télécom SudParis, France), Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA), Georgios Bouloukakis (University of Patras, Greece)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web-CozyBench a extension of &lt;a href=&#34;https://damslabumbc.github.io/publication/percom-2024/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Co-zyBench&lt;/a&gt;, a benchmarking tool for evaluating thermal comfort provision systems via Digital Twin simulations. Web-CozyBench offers an intuitive GUI to configure building/occupant scenarios, execute co-simulations, and visualize results without simulation expertise. This tool builds on Co-zyBench and will help accelerate comfort-focused smart building research and development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at SmartComp 2025!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-13-2025-smartcomp-accepted/5-13-2025-smartcomp-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-13-2025-smartcomp-accepted/5-13-2025-smartcomp-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper has been accepted at the IEEE International Conference on Smart Computing (SmartComp) 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DigiGuide: A DT-based Occupant Guiding System for Optimizing Comfort and Energy Consumption&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun Ma (Télécom SudParis, France), Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA), Georgios Bouloukakis (University of Patras, Greece)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents DigiGuide, a Digital Twin-based occupant guiding system that uses NSGA-III optimization to proactively balance energy efficiency and multi-factor comfort (thermal, acoustic, crowdedness, etc,.) across dynamic indoor environments. Validated in two large-scale settings (a co-working space and an airport), DigiGuide achieved 18.2% better comfort and 8.6% energy savings compared to baseline strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Artifact Paper award at PerCom 2025!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-23-2025-percom-artifact-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-23-2025-percom-artifact-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the analysis of smart home IoT devices while not in active use won the Best Artifact Paper award at PerCom 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Smart Home Exchanged 3M Messages: Defining and Analyzing Smart Device Passive Mode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian Badolato (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), Kaur Kullman (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), Nikolaos Papadakis (Institut Polytechnique de Paris), Manav Bhatt (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), Georgios Bouloukakis (Institut Polytechnique de Paris), Don Engel (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), and Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This award illustrates our commitment to ensuring verifiable and reproducible results through both dataset and code review. Our dataset, as well as custom datasets of your own, can be analyzed according to the methods in our paper through the scripts at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DAMSlabUMBC/Passive-Mode-Study&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Smart Home IoT Passive Mode Analysis Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo papers accepted at PerCom 2025!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/1-20-2025-percom-demos-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/1-20-2025-percom-demos-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team&amp;rsquo;s project, LiDAR Occupancy and Analysis Detection System (LOADS), has been officially accepted to be demoed at the IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications (PerCom) 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;LOADS: LiDAR-based Privacy-Preserving Queue Monitoring and Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saisricharan Malkireddy, Sumedh Kane, Sourimitra Medepalli, Satvik Racharla, Bharg Barot, Christian Badolato, Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a second demo paper accepted in collaboration with Portland State University. This work presents a system to identify suspicious trackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BL(u)E CRAB: A User-Centric Framework for Identifying Suspicious Bluetooth Trackers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dylan Conklin (Portland State University, United States), Primal Pappachan (Portland State University, United States) and Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, United States).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long queues in retail and public environments can frustrate customers and negatively impact user experiences. Traditional camera-based monitoring systems are effective in analyzing queues, however, the potential for identification raises privacy concerns. Other queue-counting methods (such as WiFi or RFID) depend on user-carried devices or tags. In contrast, LiDAR sensors strictly measure distances and angles, which drastically reduces privacy risks and does not require users to carry specialized hardware. We present LOADS, an end-to-end, single-sensor, LiDAR-based IoT solution for queue-occupancy and wait-time estimation. LOADS incorporates Hierarchical Density-Based Spatial Clustering of Applications with Noise (HDBSCAN) to provide a robust method of accurately separating people from noise in real time. We employ a SARIMAX model to predict future queue lengths from historical data stored in a time-series database. A web interface shows real-time and historical queue information, enabling users to make informed decisions. We demonstrate the feasibility of LOADS in practical retail and conference scenarios, highlighting its privacy-preserving nature, accurate crowd estimation, and simple deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the pervasiveness of Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE)-based devices, detecting unwanted or suspicious trackers is challenging, especially due to their heterogeneity, cross-platform compatibility issues, and inconsistent detection methods. BL(u)E CRAB identifies suspicious BLE trackers based on various risk factors within minutes. It does so by collecting information including the number of encounters, time with the user, distance traveled with the user, number of areas each device appeared in, and device proximity to user. After collecting this information, BL(u)E CRAB performs an outlier detection analysis to flag suspicious devices. BL(u)E CRAB presents this information in a simple, intuitive, and customizable way for the user to determine which devices pose the biggest threat to them based on their context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to presenting LOADS and BL(u)E CRAB at PerCom 2025 and discussing their potential for wide-scale deployment with the research community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at PerCom 2025!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/1-20-2025-percom-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/1-20-2025-percom-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the analysis of smart home IoT devices while not in active use has been accepted at PerCom 2025! This is Christian&amp;rsquo;s first paper accepted at a conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Smart Home Exchanged 3M Messages: Defining and Analyzing Smart Device Passive Mode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian Badolato (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), Kaur Kullman (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), Nikolaos Papadakis (Institut Polytechnique de Paris), Manav Bhatt (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), Georgios Bouloukakis (Institut Polytechnique de Paris), Don Engel (University of Maryland, Baltimore County), and Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constant connectedness of smart home devices and their sensing capabilities pose a unique threat to individuals&#39; privacy. While users may expect devices to exhibit minimal activity while they are not performing their intended functions, this is not necessarily the case, and traditional idle mode designations are insufficient to address the current landscape of smart home devices. To address this we propose a designation based on a comprehensive categorization of smart home devices. We then measure the network traffic of thirty-two devices in their respective passive modes. We find that 97% of the devices exhibit near-constant network activity in these modes (exchanging over 3M messages in 24 hours), with many of the devices initiating and responding to LAN communications with other devices, which potentially exposes users to privacy leakages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aamir&#39;s presentation at PETS 2024!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/7-1-2024-pets-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/7-1-2024-pets-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aamir Hamid did a great job today at #PETS2024 presenting our work (with Hemanth Reddy Samidi, Primal Pappachan, and Tim Finin) on designing a benchmark to evaluate GenAI systems answering questions about privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First conference presentation of (hopefully) many! Amazing job Aamir Hamid!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GenAIPABench: A Benchmark for Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aamir Hamid, Hemanth Reddy Samidi, Tim Finin (University of Maryland, Baltimore County,USA), Primal Pappachan (Portland State University,USA), Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County,USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper introduces GenAIPABench, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the performance of Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants in understanding and addressing privacy policy and data protection regulation queries. By providing a standardized framework for assessment, our work aims to propel forward the development of AI tools that support users in navigating privacy concerns more effectively. This acceptance not only highlights the importance of our research in the field of privacy technologies but also marks a significant milestone for our team&amp;rsquo;s ongoing efforts to improve digital privacy protection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at PETS 2024!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/2-1-2024-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/2-1-2024-pets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team&amp;rsquo;s research on GenAIPABench, a novel benchmark for Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants, has been officially accepted for publication at the Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS) 2024. This recognition underscores our contribution to enhancing digital privacy through AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GenAIPABench: A Benchmark for Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aamir Hamid, Hemanth Reddy Samidi, Tim Finin (University of Maryland, Baltimore County,USA), Primal Pappachan (Portland State University,USA), Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County,USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper introduces GenAIPABench, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the performance of Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants in understanding and addressing privacy policy and data protection regulation queries. By providing a standardized framework for assessment, our work aims to propel forward the development of AI tools that support users in navigating privacy concerns more effectively. This acceptance not only highlights the importance of our research in the field of privacy technologies but also marks a significant milestone for our team&amp;rsquo;s ongoing efforts to improve digital privacy protection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at PerCom 2024!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/1-26-2024-percom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/1-26-2024-percom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on a benchmark to evaluate thermal comfort provision systems on smart buildings has been accepted at PerCom 2024. More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.percom.org/list-of-accepted-paper/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PerCom 2024 website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Co-zyBench: Using Co-Simulation and Digital Twins to Benchmark Thermal Comfort Provision in Smart Buildings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun Ma (Telecom SudParis, France); Dimitrije Panic (Telecom SudParis, France); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, France)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning (HVAC) systems account for 40% to 50% of energy usage in commercial buildings. Thus, innovative ways to control and manage HVAC systems while preserving occupants&#39; comfort are required. State-of-the-art solutions employ pervasive systems with sensors or smart devices to gauge individual thermal sensations, yet assessing these methods is challenging. Real-world experiments are expensive, limited in access, and often overlook occupant and regional diversity. To address this, we introduce Co-zyBench, a benchmark tool using a Digital Twin (DT) approach for evaluating personalized thermal comfort systems. It employs a co-simulation middleware interfacing between a DT of the smart building and its HVAC system and another DT representing occupants&#39; dynamic thermal preferences in various spaces. The DTs that support Co-zyBench are generated based on information, including data captured by sensors, of the space in which the thermal comfort system has to be evaluated. Co-zyBench incorporates metrics for energy consumption, thermal comfort, and occupant equality. It also features reference DTs based on standard buildings, HVAC systems, and occupants with diverse thermal preferences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at Midd4DT@Middleware 2023!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/12-11-2023-middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/12-11-2023-middleware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on a benchmark to evaluate thermal comfort provision systems on smart buildings has been accepted at the 1st International Workshop on Middleware for Digital Twin (Midd4DT) collocated with Middleware 2023. More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hakiri.github.io/Midd4DT/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Midd4DT 2023 website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DEMSA: a DT-enabled Middleware for Self-adaptive Smart Spaces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun Ma (Telecom SudParis, France); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, France); Ajay Kattepur (Ericsson AI Research, India); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Denis Conan (Telecom SudParis, France);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning (HVAC) systems account for a significant portion of energy consumption within buildings. In order to balance the effect of thermal comfort vis-a-vis energy savings, HVAC control strategies have been proposed. However, the strategies are static and do not take into account dynamic changes of consumers, hence creating sub-optimal outcomes. This paper proposes DEMSA, a Digital Twin (DT)-enabled middleware for the self-adaptation of smart buildings. The DEMSA middleware interconnects and coordinates intelligent data exchange between the building edge server, digital twin and Artificial Intelligence (AI) planning nodes in order to invoke appropriate strategies. Moreover, DEMSA is paired with a self-adaptive mechanism that can detect the anomaly of generated planning and adaptively modify it. This process ensures balancing building energy consumption and thermal comfort requirements, without human intervention. The DEMSA middleware is described over a real smart space scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Presentation at The University System of Maryland’s Louis Stokes Alliance for Minority Participation Symposium 2024</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/12-2-2023-lsamp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/12-2-2023-lsamp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A member of the smartCampus project team at DAMS (Nikki Cayas, University of Maryland, Baltimore County) presented a poster at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lsamp.umbc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The University System of Maryland’s Louis Stokes Alliance for Minority Participation&lt;/a&gt; Symposium 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikki presented the team&amp;rsquo;s ongoing research that seeks to improve the quality of life for individuals by identifying the most comfortable work location for users in a controlled environment. Through the transformation of raw quantitative data captured by decibel, degree, and motion sensors into human-comprehensible notions, such as noise level, temperature, and occupancy level, we are capable of determining the most optimal work location for users based on their comfortability preferences. We anticipate uncovering valuable trends related to user preferences and the effectiveness of our data collection, translation, and protection processes. Looking ahead, we envision deploying our product in the library at the University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC) to provide a valuable resource that enhances the study processes for UMBC students. As our research unfolds, we hope to continue improving user comfort in work and positively impacting daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Presentation at the Annual Biomedical Research Conference For Minoritized Scientists 2023 in Phoenix, Arizona</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/11-30-23-abrcms-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/11-30-23-abrcms-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, Ruhshana received the opportunity to attend the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.abrcms.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Annual Biomedical Research Conference For Minoritized Scientists Conference (ABRCMS 2023)&lt;/a&gt; to present her group&amp;rsquo;s research poster focused on analyzing health conditions, privacy, and utility tradeoffs in smart home devices. ABRCMS took place in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research abstract and poster written and contributed to by Ruhshana Bobojonova, Luke Zimmerman, Tartela Tabassum, Josh Cheeks, and Dr. Roberto Yus were approved by the ABRCMS committee, and Ruhshana received the opportunity to present at one of the biggest biomedical research conferences in the nation. Ruhshana also attended workshops focused on setting students up for success in graduate school as well as networked with representatives from universities and biomedical companies. One of the biggest things that stood out to Ruhshana was UMBC&amp;rsquo;s big representation in the conference. There were many keynote speakers, faculty, and students who represented UMBC!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper on genAI and privacy published on arXiv</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/10-9-2023-arxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/10-9-2023-arxiv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on genAI and privacy has been published on arXiv. More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.05138&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arxiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GENAIPABENCH: A Benchmark for Generative AI-based Privacy Assistants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aamir Hamid(University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); 
Hemanth Reddy Samidi (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA)
Tim Finin (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); 
Primal Pappachan (Portland State University, Portland, USA);
Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the age of data-driven technology, privacy has emerged as a critical concern for both users
and organizations. Privacy policies are widely used to outline the data management practices of
a company. However, it has been demonstrated that privacy policies, as well as regulations, are
generally too complex for people, which motivates the need for privacy assistants. The emergence
of generative AI (genAI) technology presents an opportunity to improve the capabilities of privacy
assistants to answer questions people might have about their privacy. However, while textual genAI
technology generates content that seems accurate, it is been shown that it can generate fake/incorrect
information (e.g., due to its tendency to hallucinate) which might mislead the user. This paper
presents, GENAIPABENCH, a novel privacy benchmark to evaluate the performance of generative
AI-based privacy assistants (GenAIPAs). GENAIPABENCH includes: 1. A comprehensive set of
questions about an organization’s privacy policy along with annotated answers and data protection
regulation questions; 2. A set of metrics to evaluate the answers obtained from the generative AI
system; 3. An evaluation tool that generates appropriate prompts to introduce the system to the
privacy document and different variations of the privacy questions to evaluate its robustness. We
present an evaluation of OpenAI’s ChatGPT using GENAIPABENCH. Our findings indicate that
ChatGPT holds considerable promise as a privacy agent, although it experiences challenges such as
handling complex tasks, ensuring response consistency, and accurately referencing the information provided.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper on privacy policies and IoT published on arXiv</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/11-8-2023-arxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/11-8-2023-arxiv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on privacy policies of IoT devices has been published on arXiv. More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.05890&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arxiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PrivacyLens: A Framework to Collect and Analyze the Landscape of Past, Present, and Future Smart Device Privacy Policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aamir Hamid(University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); 
Hemanth Reddy Samidi (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA)
Tim Finin (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); 
Primal Pappachan (Portland State University, Portland, USA);
Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the adoption of smart devices continues to permeate all
aspects of our lives, concerns surrounding user privacy have
become more pertinent than ever before. While privacy policies define the data management practices of their manufacturers, previous work has shown that they are rarely read and
understood by users. Hence, automatic analysis of privacy
policies has been shown to help provide users with appropriate insights. Previous research has extensively analyzed
privacy policies of websites, e-commerce, and mobile applications, but privacy policies of smart devices, present some
differences and specific challenges such as the difficulty to
find and collect them. We present PrivacyLens, a novel framework for discovering and collecting past, present, and future
smart device privacy policies and harnessing NLP and ML algorithms to analyze them. PrivacyLens is currently deployed,
collecting, analyzing, and publishing insights about privacy
policies to assist different stakeholders of smart devices, such
as users, policy authors, and regulators. We show several examples of analytical tasks enabled by PrivacyLens, including
comparisons of devices per type and manufacturing country,
categorization of privacy policies, and impact of data regulations on data practices. At the time of submitting this paper,
PrivacyLens had collected and analyzed more than 1,200 privacy policies for 7,300 smart devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master&#39;s Thesis Defense!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/7-27-2023-thesis-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/7-27-2023-thesis-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sragvi Nidamarti successfully defended his Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis &amp;lsquo;Addressing Trust Concerns in the Electric Vehicle Supply Chain: A
Knowledge Graph Approach&amp;rsquo;. The study discusses the socio-economic impact of EV batteries and addresses the trust concerns surrounding it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committee : Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA) ; Tim Finnin (University of Maryland, Baltimore County) ; Manas Gaur(University of Maryland, Baltimore County); Konstantinos Mersinas (Royal Holloway University of London)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers are increasingly interested in electric vehicles in comparison to gasoline vehicles, resulting in a significant rise in sales in recent years. This change is
heavily attributed to factors such as high-quality manufacturing and environmental concerns. However, customers may have concerns regarding the eco-friendliness of
the manufacturing process involved and the socio-economic impact (labor law violations) of batteries, possibly due to the newness of the technology involved and a
lack of transparency in the process and supply chain. This thesis presents a system to help build trust around this concern. It has a knowledge graph that acts
as a base representing standard elements of trust, constructed as an integration of state-of-the-art ontologies in the field. It also includes knowledge about the manufacturing process and the supply chain. With this information, the system uses a
mechanism to address the concerns using SPARQL queries that can, among others, label potential trust issues in the manufacturing of electric vehicles. We showcase a
use case in which we identify trust issues in certain popular EV manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergrad Student Presentation at UMBC&#39;s URCAD 2023</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-3-2023-umbc-urcad2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-3-2023-umbc-urcad2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our undergrad team (Tartela, Luke, Ruhshana, and Josh) presented their research poster at UMBC&amp;rsquo;s Undergraduate Research and Creative Achievement Day (URCAD) 2023. UMBC has made a special mention to their work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://umbc.edu/stories/urcad-2023/#:~:text=Balancing%20privacy%20and%20utility%20in%20smart%20devices%C2%A0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;their website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Tartela, Luke, Ruhshana, and Josh on their impressive group research project! Their exploration of the balance between privacy and utility in smart devices is a complex and timely topic in today&amp;rsquo;s world. The prototype framework they built showcases their creativity and technical skills in utilizing open-source code, artificial intelligence, and machine learning algorithms to generate and protect inferences based on audio and video input. Their focus on giving users more autonomy over their privacy is commendable, and their work will contribute to ongoing discussions and efforts to address privacy concerns in smart spaces. Well done to all four students on their outstanding work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster accepted for presentation at UMBC&#39;s URCAD 2023</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-8-2023-umbc-urcad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-8-2023-umbc-urcad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our undergrad team looking at privacy issues on smart homes (Tartela, Luke, Ruhshana, and Josh) will present a poster during UMBC&amp;rsquo;s Undergraduate Research and Creative Achievement Day (URCAD) 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyzing Privacy and Utility Tradeoffs in Smart Homes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tartela Tabassum, Luke Zimmermann, Ruhshana Bobojonova, Joshua Cheeks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this research is to explore the trade-off that exists between privacy and utility when using smart devices at home. Smart speakers, doorbells, and TVs are becoming pervasive but raise important privacy concerns. For instance, by collecting audio and video, one could learn private information about us such as our age, emotions, socioeconomic status, and health conditions. To increase trust, there is a need to inform people about potentially sensitive inferences that can be made about them by smart devices and give them a choice to consent to it. We have built a prototype of a framework, using open-source code and AI/ML algorithms, that generates inferences about an individual based on audio (e.g., speech data collected by a smart speaker) and video (e.g., images collected by a smart security camera). The framework also allows the user to select which of these inferences should be &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo;. We have explored different mechanisms to hide those inferences while preserving utility such as: removing specific portions of audio/video that can lead to whether the person might be facing a respiratory disease or modifying the pitch/tone to hide their age and mood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at ICMLA 2022</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/9-1-2022-icmla/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/9-1-2022-icmla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on one-shot federated learning has been accepted at ICMLA 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One-Shot Federated Group Collaborative Filtering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maksim E. Eren (UMBC/LANL), Manish Bhattarai (LANL), Nicholas Solovyev (LANL), Luke E. Richards (UMBC), Roberto Yus (UMBC), Charles Nicholas (UMBC), Boian S. Alexandrov (LANL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) with missing-value completion is a well-known effective Collaborative Filtering (CF) method used to provide personalized user recommendations. However, traditional CF relies on a privacy-invasive collection of user data to build a central recommender model. One-shot federated learning has recently emerged as a method to mitigate the privacy problem while addressing the traditional communication bottleneck of federated learning. In this paper, we present the first one-shot federated CF implementation, named One-FedCF, for groups of users or collaborating organizations. In our solution, the clients first apply local CF in-parallel to build distinct, client-specific recommenders. Then, the privacy-preserving local item patterns and biases from each client are shared with the processor to perform joint factorization in order to extract the global item patterns. Extracted patterns are then aggregated to each client to build the local models via knowledge distillation. In our experiments, we demonstrate the feasibility of our approach with two MovieLens datasets. One-FedCF can obtain results competitive with the state-of-the-art federated recommender systems at a substantial decrease in the number of communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at CIKM 2022</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/8-1-2022-sentaur-cikm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/8-1-2022-sentaur-cikm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on supporting sensor-based smart space analytical applications has been accepted at CIKM 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sentaur: Sensor Observable Data Model for Smart Spaces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peeyush Gupta, Sharad Mehrotra (University of California, Irvine); Shantanu Sharma (New Jersey Institute of Technology); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County); and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents Sentaur, a middleware designed, built, and deployed to support sensor-based smart space analytical applications. Sentaur supports a powerful data model that decouples semantic data (about the application domain) from sensor data (using which the semantic data is derived). By supporting mechanisms to map/translate data, concepts, and queries between the two levels, Sentaur relieves application developers from having to know or reason about either capabilities of sensors or write sensor specific code. This paper describes Sentaur data model, its translation strategy, and highlights its benefits through real-world case studies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at VLDB 2022</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/6-16-2022-jenner-vldb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/6-16-2022-jenner-vldb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on supporting query-time enrichment has been accepted at VLDB 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;JENNER:  Just-in-time Enrichment in Query Processing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dhrubajyoti Ghosh, Peeyush Gupta, and Sharad Mehrotra (University of California, Irvine); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County); and Yasser Altowim (Saudi Data and Artificial Intelligence Authority)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging domains, such as sensor-driven smart spaces and social media analytics, require incoming data to be enriched prior to its use. Enrichment often consists of machine learning (ML) functions that are too expensive/infeasible to execute at ingestion. We develop a strategy entitled Just-in-time ENrichmeNt in quERy Processing (JENNER) to support interactive analytics over data as soon as it arrives for such application context. JENNER exploits the inherent tradeoffs of cost and quality often displayed by the ML functions to  progressively improve query answers during query execution. We describe how JENNER works for a large class of SPJ and aggregation queries that form the bulk of  data analytics workload. Our experimental results on real datasets (IoT and Tweet) show that JENNER achieves progressive answers performing significantly better than the naive strategies of achieving progressive computation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UMBC faculty Karimi and Yus help team win 2nd place in Sandpit Challenge on Digital Trust</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-15-2022-incs-coe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/5-15-2022-incs-coe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A research team that includes UMBC CSEE faculty Naghmeh Karimi and Roberto Yus won the second place prize in the 2022 INCS-CoE Sandpit Challenge on Digital Trust. The International Cyber Security Center of Excellence (INCS-CoE) is an international collaboration of government, industry, and academic organizations that have partnered to explore pioneering efforts to address cybersecurity challenges created by a growing borderless digital society.  UMBC is a charter member of INCS-CoE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The INCS-COE Sandpit Challenge invited self-assembled teams to compete for seed research funding prizes to pursue their work further. The UMBC faculty teamed up with researchers from Royal Holloway (UK) and Keio University (Japan). They were awarded second prize for their proposal to deal with challenges associated with developing an International Digital Trust Framework. In particular, their project proposal focused on designing an ontology-based interoperability solution amongst the US, UK, and Japan for mutual recognition of trust, capturing private and public sector use cases with different assurance levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at ACM TOIT</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-27-2022-semiotic-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-27-2022-semiotic-journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on facilitating the administration of smart spaces has been accepted in ACM Transactions on Internet Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SemIoTic Ecosystem: A Semantic Bridge between IoT Devices and Smart Spaces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, USA); Sharad Mehrotra and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart space administration and application development is challenging in part due to the semantic gap that exists between the high-level requirements of users and the low-level capabilities of IoT devices. The stakeholders in a smart space are required to deal with communicating with specific IoT devices, capturing data, processing it, and abstracting it out to generate useful inferences. Additionally, this makes reusability of smart space applications difficult since they are developed for specific sensor deployments. In this paper, we present a holistic approach to IoT smart spaces, the SemIoTic ecosystem, to facilitate application development, space management, and service provision to its inhabitants. The ecosystem is based on a centralized repository, where developers can advertise their space-agnostic applications; and a SemIoTic system deployed in each smart space that interacts with those applications to provide them with the required information. SemIoTic applications are developed using a metamodel that defines high-level concepts abstracted from the smart space about the space itself and the people within it. Application requirements can be expressed then in terms of user-friendly high-level concepts which are automatically translated by SemIoTic into sensor/actuator commands adapted to the underlying device deployment in each space. We present a reference implementation of the ecosystem that has been deployed at the University of California, Irvine and is abstracting data from hundreds of sensors in the space and providing applications to campus members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best paper award at PerCom 2022!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-25-2022-percom-smartspec-best-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/3-25-2022-percom-smartspec-best-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the generation of realistic synthetic IoT datasets won the Mark Weiser Best Paper Award at IEEE PERCOM 2022!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SmartSPEC: Customizable Smart Space Datasets via Event-Driven Simulations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Chio (University of California, Irvine, USA); Daokun Jiang (Google); Peeyush Gupta (University of California, Irvine, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, USA); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Sharad Mehrotra and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents SmartSPEC, an approach to generate customizable smart space datasets using sensorized spaces in which people and events are embedded. Smart space datasets are critical to design, deploy and evaluate robust systems and applications to ensure cost-effective operation and safety/comfort/convenience of the space occupants. Often, real-world data is difficult to obtain due to the lack of fine-grained sensing; privacy/security concerns prevent the release and sharing of individual and spatial data. SmartSPEC is a smart space simulator and data generator that can create a digital representation (twin) of a smart space and its activities. SmartSPEC uses a semantic model and ML-based approaches to characterize and learn attributes in a sensorized space, and applies an event-driven simulation strategy to generate realistic simulated data about the space (events, trajectories, sensor datasets, etc). To evaluate the realism of the data generated by SmartSPEC, we develop a structured methodology and metrics to assess various aspects of smart space datasets, including trajectories of people and occupancy of spaces. Our experimental study looks at two real-world settings/datasets: an instrumented smart campus building and a city-wide GPS dataset. Our results show that the trajectories produced by SmartSPEC are 1.4x to 4.4x more realistic than the best synthetic data baseline when compared to real-world data, depending on the scenario and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at PerCom 2022!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/2-14-2022-percom-smartspec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/2-14-2022-percom-smartspec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the generation of realistic synthetic IoT datasets has been accepted at PerCom 2022. The paper has also been nominated for best paper award! More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.percom.org/full-program/#session5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PerCom 2022 website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SmartSPEC: Customizable Smart Space Datasets via Event-Driven Simulations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Chio (University of California, Irvine, USA); Daokun Jiang (Google); Peeyush Gupta (University of California, Irvine, USA); Georgios Bouloukakis (Telecom SudParis, USA); Roberto Yus (University of Maryland, Baltimore County, USA); Sharad Mehrotra and Nalini Venkatasubramanian (University of California, Irvine, USA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents SmartSPEC, an approach to generate customizable smart space datasets using sensorized spaces in which people and events are embedded. Smart space datasets are critical to design, deploy and evaluate robust systems and applications to ensure cost-effective operation and safety/comfort/convenience of the space occupants. Often, real-world data is difficult to obtain due to the lack of fine-grained sensing; privacy/security concerns prevent the release and sharing of individual and spatial data. SmartSPEC is a smart space simulator and data generator that can create a digital representation (twin) of a smart space and its activities. SmartSPEC uses a semantic model and ML-based approaches to characterize and learn attributes in a sensorized space, and applies an event-driven simulation strategy to generate realistic simulated data about the space (events, trajectories, sensor datasets, etc). To evaluate the realism of the data generated by SmartSPEC, we develop a structured methodology and metrics to assess various aspects of smart space datasets, including trajectories of people and occupancy of spaces. Our experimental study looks at two real-world settings/datasets: an instrumented smart campus building and a city-wide GPS dataset. Our results show that the trajectories produced by SmartSPEC are 1.4x to 4.4x more realistic than the best synthetic data baseline when compared to real-world data, depending on the scenario and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DAMS Research Group is officially launched!</title>
      <link>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/10-24-21-group-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damslabumbc.github.io/post/10-24-21-group-starts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DAta Management &amp;amp; Semantics (DAMS) research group starts at the University of Maryland, Baltimore County.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
